A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Accounting Service FA216
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Accounting Service
1901-1930
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
FA216
5.24 Cubic Feet 5 boxes
4 5" hollingers & 1 2½" hollinger.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Received from Accounting Service in February 1981.
Scope and Contents note
These boxes contain account books, cash books, check books, journal and ledger books, and also notebooks.
The notebooks also appear to be concerned with experiments (especially scientific solutions) rather than money. Cross-references have been made in the card catalog under the person's name.
Arrangement note
Arranged in chronological order with the exception of the notebooks, which are arranged according to the person's name. The dates are not always in perfect order - ie, the Cash books overlap each other (See Box 2, Folders 3-4).
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 280
Conditions Governing Access note
This collection is open for research.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment.
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Medicine, Preventive; Medical sciences; Medical research; Rockefeller University; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
- Account and Cash Books
  - Account Books. The Corn Exchange Bank, Lexington Branch, New York, 1915 February 15-1928 January 21 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Account Book. The Corn Exchange Bank, Lexington Branch, New York, 1922 June 30-1926 April 30 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Account Book. The Corn Exchange Bank, Lexington Branch, New York. Payroll Account, 1926 February 13-1929 January 29 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Account Book. The Corn Exchange Bank, Lexington Branch, New York, 1926 May 1-1930 June 30 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Account Book. The Corn Exchange Bank, Lexington Branch, New York. A.D. Robertson, Bursar's Special Account, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Account Book. Princeton Bank and Trust Company, Princeton, New Jersey, 1917 March 9-1927 June 19 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Account Book. Princeton Bank and Trust Company, Princeton, New Jersey. Payroll Account, 1926 April 13-1928 June 27 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Cash Book. Cover: "Institute Acct. March 1906-August 1907", 1906-1907 August; 168 pp. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Cash Book. Cover: "Board of Health 1906", 1905-1907; 7 pp. entries (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Scope and Contents note
    Includes 19 pp. insert (loose, some half-size) bills & expense statements.
  - Cash Book. Petty Cash, Institute Account, 1904 October-1906 February (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Cash Book. Petty Cash, 1908 April-1909 March (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Cash Book. Hospital, Petty Cash, 1908 October 12-1910 September 26; (4 pp. entries) (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Cash and Check Books
  - Cash Book, 1910 April 1-1910 December 30 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Cash Book. Petty Cash, 1916 November 4-1917 June 30 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Cash Book, 1917 August 24-1918 December 23 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Cash Book, 1917 June 21-1918 March 15 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Cash Book. Inside Cover, 1918 December 18-1919 December 31; 180 pp. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Cash Book, 1919 December 13-1920 December 11 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Check Book, 1901 July 3-1904 October 11 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    (501 entries, with 3 loose pages, "Copy of Appropriations for 1903-1904 voted at meeting Rockefeller Institute, held June 1903").
- Journal and Ledger Books
  - Journal Book. Petty Cash, 1918 January-1919 April (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Ledger Book, 1920 December 8-1921 September 30; 164 pp. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Ledger Book, 1921 September 2-1922 June 30 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Ledger Book, 1922 May 30-1923 May 5 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Journal Book, 1923 May 3-1923 June 30 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Notebooks: Louis Sattler and James K. Senior
  - Notebook. Cover: 1914-1915. Inside page: "Louis Sattler, Room 207" (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Notebook. Cover: 1915-1916. Inside page: "Louis Sattler, Room 210, Sept 14, 1915. Kjedahl Book #2" Kjedahl Book #3", 1915 September 14 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Notebook. Inside cover: "Louis Sattler, Room 505", 1916 November 20 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Notebook. Inside page: "James K. Senior, Room 207. Louis Sattler", 1915 June 9 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Laboratory Notebook. Cover: "James K. Senior, Room 207, 1-100", 1915 February 2; (with 6 pages laboratory notes inserted) 95 pp. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Notebook. Cover: "James K. Senior, Room 210. 301-400", undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Notebook. Inside facing page: "James K. Senior, Room 210", undated; 15 pp. entries (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Notebooks: F.M. Mader and H.C. Ward
  - Notebook. Inside cover: "F.M. Mader, #2", 1905 April 4-June 30 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Notebook. Inside cover: "Book #1, H.C. Ward. Short General Index on the last page", 1905 April 7-1905 circa May 30 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks. (3 bound together) H.C. Ward, Books # 2, 3, 4, 1905 May 3-circa July 1905 (Box 5, Folder 3)